<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sir, my lord major and the aldermen his brethren, upon serious consideration, for the good of the city, has thought fit to set out an order against making, buying, selling, or flinging, of squibs; being an unlawful trade: and not only so, but they have commanded the citizens of this city, that they do not permit their children, or servants, to make, throw, or fire, any fire-works, ...</title>
            <author>James, Elinor. ca. 1645-1719.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B25208</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886142</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186029</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240890714</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing J421</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide T.100*[61]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225511</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886142</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886142e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B25208)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186029)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C3:2[60])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Sir, my lord major and the aldermen his brethren, upon serious consideration, for the good of the city, has thought fit to set out an order against making, buying, selling, or flinging, of squibs; being an unlawful trade: and not only so, but they have commanded the citizens of this city, that they do not permit their children, or servants, to make, throw, or fire, any fire-works, ...</title>
                  <author>James, Elinor. ca. 1645-1719.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from first lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Signed: Elianor James.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Fireworks --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">London (England) --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:186029:1"/>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>MY Lord Major and the Aldermen his Brethren, upon serious Consideration, for the good of the City, has thought fit to set out an Order against Making, Buying, Selling, or Flinging, of Squibs; being an unlawful Trade: and not only so, but they have Commanded the Citizens of this City, that they do not permit their Children, or Servants, to Make, Throw, or Fire, any Fire-Works, in the Streets or out of their Houses, Balconies, or other places; nor that they suffer any Persons to come into, or remain in their Houses who may be guilty of such Offences. For my Lord Major and the Aldermen his Brethren are fully resolv'd to use the uttermost of their Power with all severity, against those who will not obey: and therefore out of a tender care that not any one should come to trouble through ignorance, They have Commanded the Beadles of every Ward, to go from House to House, to declare their Intentions. And it is to be hoped, that every sincere Christian will be obedient, when they know they are Commanded thereunto: for no Man can plead ignorance, for all Men know how hurtful and injurious they be. And there's not any Man can think that my Lord Major has not power to punish those that hurt and destroy the King's Subjects: I can assure you, He has a power (or else how should He keep the Peace?) for He represents the King in the City. And it's a shame that in a Christian City there should be such Hellish-practices, as is not acted in any City in the known World besides: And is it not a shame that we who should be the best, are worst? For would it not be a fine sight for to see rich Carpets hung out, and Persons of Quality well Dressed in the Balconies, and other People standing in Ranges in good order, and People passing to and fro without fear? this would be a joy and comfort: but as the City is made now, I can compare it to nothing but Hell: your Windows taken down, and Men tuck'd up flinging Serpents one at another, as if they would destroy each other; I can compare them to nothing but Furies spitting Fire one at another: methinks it's a shame for rational Men to imitate the Devil, to burn and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroy. But that which grieves me worst of all is, that you have corrupted Women-kind, for they should be Innocent, Sincere, and Modest, and Tender-hearted, and afraid to do a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny thing that is injurious; and I am sorry their Natures should be chang'd; but it's fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> want of Consideration; and I dont doubt any will be guilty of this Crime, when they consider it. And there's several Honourable Citizens, has told me, that they have neither suffered Friends nor Servants to fling any Squibs out of their Houses, no, not Lords; and they are resolv'd to continue in the same mind; and they will be Wise: and I hope you will all do the same. I find your Beadles are much to blame, for they have not obeyed their Orders; for I have inquired, and find but here and there one that has had notice: and therefore, I am resolv'd to be very diligent in this matter my self; for I have great hopes of the Young-Men (and I doubt not their obedience, if the Magistrates are Zealous, and the Officers behave themselves like Men) for they all carry themselves very civilly towards me; and I hope there's not any one but what will do the same: for God and good Me<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> hate Evil: and I am not an Enemy to any thing, but what's hurtful either to Soul or Body▪ and I can assure you, that this Custom of flinging Squibs, is more injurious to the soul than you can imagine, by reason it makes Youth bold and delight in mischief, the more mischie they do, the more they rejoice, Devil like: and this gives the Devil great advantages and I doubt not, but by God's Grace, you will find great benefit by desisting: which the Lord grant, <hi>Amen, Amen.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>So I rest your Friend and Souls Well-wisher ELIANOR JAMES</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>